No man should control your energy
because energy is from the earth. It was
put here by God for humans to use it and
I think it is a crime that we've been
buying and selling it for so long. Need
to know info for anybody who wants to
live truly off grid. Solar has come a
long way in the last 5 years, but the
main problem we have is with peak
ampacity. Each one of these inverters
will produce 10 kW of energy. That's
about 42 amps at 230 volts. [music]
That's not quite enough to run an
electric range and much less my entire
homestead. In order to overcome this
problem, you must do some solar
scientist-ing. Luckily, I am a solar
scientist who can help you understand
solar. In order to overcome the ampacity
shortfall, you have to wire inverters in
parallel. I must warn you that not all
products have this capability, so you
have to check the manufacturer
specifications. The Big Battery Apex I'm
installing in Costa Rica has that
capability and here's how you wire in
parallel. What you do is take the load
wires from each one of your inverters
and wire them into a combiner box first.
All your hots go into a properly sized
breaker since this puts out about 43
amps at 230, I have them on 15 amp
breakers. And the combiner box allows
all the energy to combine and balance
before you send it up in your main wires
to your load panel. This is my load
panel where I'll provide all the energy
for everything on the homestead. This
panel is currently providing all of the
loads for the homestead. That wire up
there is the hated wire coming from the
county that I cannot wait to take out of
here. All I have left to do is install a
100 amp breaker here, run a number two
copper wire over here, snatch that
stupid government wire out, and plug it
in. Then I hook up all my batteries,
connect them to the inverters, flip the
switches, and we're on. Solar is very
complicated for a lot of people, but I'm
here to make it simple for you. That way
you can find your freedom and live off
grid. No man should control your energy
because energy is from the earth. It was
put here by God for humans to use it and
I think it is a crime that we've been
buying and selling it for so long. Got a
couple more wires to run, couple
batteries to hook up, and this place
will be off grid and I can't wait to
show you what OG stands for off grid,
baby. My name is Tico Joe, your Puerto
Rican solar scientist. Ouch.